

# Ilkka Kudjoi

Date of birth 18.1.1982

Curriculum Vitae

I have already eleven years of experience in the software industry in versatile tasks. Currently I'm more focused on backend, most of all on databases, but I have also been a Full Stack Developer. I love solving complex prolems, building CI/CD pipelines on database solutions and automating ETL processes. Feedback from customers has always been commendatory. I commute by bike almost every working day of the year and besides that I also live cross-country skiing, orienteering and also running without checkpoint targets. I also enjoy woodworks.

### Education

2002–2007 Master of Science in Technology, Helsinki University of Technology

2006–2007 **Erasmus Exchange**, *University of Würzburg* 

2001–2002 Military service, Kainuu Brigade, Kajaani

#### Master's thesis

**Topic** Applying the Gittins index to scheduling of a queueing system

Supervisors Esko Valkeila, Samuel Aalto

Description The objective of the thesis is to introduce reader to the Gittins index and

demonstrate, how it can be applied to manage a queueing system.

E-thesis http://web.lib.aalto.fi/fi/oa/db/INSSI/?cmd=get&id=35549

# Employment

# 03/2019- Senior Software Designer, ANALYSE<sup>2</sup>

I moved to position of Senior Software Designer, because I wanted to give a teammate chance to take over the Team Lead responsibilities. The role change enables me to focus solely on the implementation of the 2nd gen data platform on Snowflake.

#### 03/2010-03/2019 Team Lead, ANALYSE<sup>2</sup>

I have been in Team Lead position in three kind of teams. First I led a team whose assignment was to further develop the Assortment Planning solution. From November 2014 our teams reorganized and we started developing a common data platform for our products, but our team also provided product support and took care of operative issues. During year 2018 the latter part of the responsibilities of the team were transferred to other teams, and we are now focused on the database development. Currently we are rebuilding our Data Vault on Snowflake Cloud.

#### 12/2015–03/2018 **Product Owner**, ANALYSE<sup>2</sup>

I managed our internal data platform development to match both internal and external needs. The responsibility was transferred to other team member as I left for paternity leave in April 2018 and after my return on October 2018 I focused on the Team Lead role only.

## 01/2008-02/2010 Software Designer, ANALYSE<sup>2</sup>

I joined Analyse $^2$  as a fresh graduate and quickly acquired new skills that were needed in the job. I became a Full Stack Developer whose task was to develop the first proper version of Analyse $^2$  Assortment Planning and Pricing solutions with MSSQL, .NET and Adobe Flex.

03/2007–12/2007 **Research Assistant**, HELSINKI UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY I worked at Networking Laboratory writing my Master's Thesis.

09/2003-12/2005 Course assistant, Helsinki University of Technology

As an course assistant I was responsible of conducting weekly exercise sessions for undergraduate students in different courses on mathemathics courses L1 and L2.

05/2004-08/2004 Research Assistant, Helsinki University of Technology

I made two special assignments during two consecutive summers at the Laboratory of Computer and Information Science at TKK.

05/2003-08/2003 Research Assistant, Helsinki University of Technology

# Programming skills

Languages C#, SQL, HTML, CSS, Ruby,

& Python, Bash, LATEX Scripting

Technologies .NET, .NET Core, AWS, & CloudFormation, Git, SVN, Frameworks SSIS, SSAS

OS Linux, Windows

Database MSSQL, Snowflake

Methods Object-oriented programming, TDD, IaC, Data Vault, Continuous integration & (TeamCity, GitLab), Agile methods, Scrum

**Patterns** 

Languages

Native Finnish

Good English German Swedish

**Basics** Russian

Links

Master's thesis Linkedin